Amber Joy

amber.joy@gmail.com | 651-247-3828 http://www.linkedin.com/in/theamberjoy http://github.com/the-amber-joy

Summary

An independent, motivated learner, avid technophile, and an eager early adopter of new technologies, I have worked as a field archaeologist, an administrative specialist, and an asset-management professional with the Veritas (formerly Symantec) NetBackup development team, and I'm now making a career transition into software development. I am passionate about lifelong learning, constant self-improvement, and finding new ways for technology to help improve our lives. My experience includes spoken and written communications; developing and writing software applications (as an individual, and in group & pair dynamics); active learning; critical thinking; troubleshooting & problem-solving; and time & resource management.

Tech Skills & Competencies

JavaScript	HTML	Passport	Grunt
Node.js / Express.js	CSS	OAuth	Windows
PHP	Sass / SCSS	JSON	MacOS
AngularJS	Bootstrap	AJAX	Git
jQuery	Handlebars	API	Heroku
MongoDB	Jade / Pug	PostgreSQL	Trello / Kanban

Professional Experience

Prime Digital Academy

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT STUDENT

2015-2016

(Prime Digital Academy is an 18-week accelerated learning program teaching foundational software engineering skills through a full MEAN stack development curriculum.)

- ❖ Personal Capstone Project "Done List App"
 - Designed and built a productivity application which operates as a reverse to-do list. App allows the user to log into a personal account and track all tasks accomplished that day, and to view a history of accomplishments over the past week, or any other selected range of dates.
 - > Technologies used in development of this application:
 - PostgreSQL (9.5.0), Express.js (4.13.4), AngularJS (1.4.9), Node.js (5.4.1), Passport (0.3.2)
 - Interface design: HTML5, CSS3, Sass (3.4.21), Bootstrap (3.3.6)
- Group Capstone Project "Talk Nerdy To Me: Toastmasters App"
 - ➤ Worked on a team of four students to develop a web application within a 2-week timeframe for the "Talk Nerdy To Me" Toastmasters chapter at The Nerdery in Bloomington, MN.
 - App was designed to allow club members to view agendas, track their progress in the Toastmasters organization, request to speak at upcoming meetings, and view statistics on their own speeches. Admin access allowed management of club roster, upcoming agendas, and site content.
 - My responsibilities in this app started with wire framing the design using Balsamiq, then organizing and building the server/database interactions. During later phases, I moved into a full-stack role where I was responsible for several parts of the application from front end to database.
 - > Technologies used in development of this application:
 - PostgreSQL (9.5.0), Express.js (4.13.4), AngularJS (1.4.9), Node.js (5.4.1), Passport (0.3.2), OAuth (2.0)

Professional Experience (continued)

Symantec Corporation (now Veritas Technologies)

ASSOCIATE LAB ANALYST

2009-2011

- Planned and tracked quarterly \$1.5-million-dollar capital budget for NetBackup Engineering department in Roseville, MN.
- Negotiated with hardware and software vendors to obtain optimal pricing, and secured quotes for creating orders.
- Created hardware/software order requisitions, planned lab deployment of all inbound hardware each quarter, and managed annual purchase and renewals of software licenses.

ADMINISTRATIVE SPECIALIST

2005-2009

- Provided calendar, scheduling, and administrative support for Senior Director of NetBackup Development, and for approximately 25 other departmental managers as needed.
- Arranged domestic and international travel for management team and development engineers.
- ❖ Took notes for distribution at weekly departmental manager meetings.
- Collected project data from management team to compile into consolidated spreadsheets and PowerPoint presentations for Senior Director.
- Provided team support for Microsoft SharePoint Server; including adding/removing users; updating access levels; and creation of sites, document libraries, and surveys.

RECEPTIONIST / ADMINISTRATIVE ASSISTANT

2004-2005

(Contracted for Veritas through Cushman & Wakefield)

- Operated multi-line switchboard supporting approximately 500 employees.
- ❖ Issued and tracked Security Badges for all site visitors.
- Maintained monthly office supply inventory; ordered & stocked needed items.
- * Responsible for maintaining all local electronic employee online directories.
- Designed and maintained internal web page for weekly office cafeteria menu; designed and printed daily menus to be posted in the café.

Education

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEERING CERTIFICATE

2016

Prime Digital Academy

BACHELOR OF ARTS, CUM LAUDE | MAJOR: ANTHROPOLOGY | MINOR: SPEECH COMMUNICATIONS

2003

Minnesota State University Moorhead

Volunteer / Community Service

International MOMS Club (Forest Lake, MN Chapter)

MEMBERSHIP VP 2013-2014

Managed new member recruitment and welcoming activities, and club membership renewals. Handled distribution of club information to new and renewing members, renewal reminders and dues collection, and collection & filing of signed waivers & other membership documents.

CHAPTER TREASURER 2012-2013

Managed finances, including club dues, expenses, donations, and tax reports for a club with around 40 members, managing an annual budget of approximately \$2500.